fpd.ie 2017-12-18

# Privacy Policy | Free Competitions | FPD.ie

This privacy statement was last reviewed March 2017.

This privacy statement covers the site [www.Freeprizedraws.ie](http://www.freeprizedraws.ie/)

Dataxcel Ltd is the registered owner of this site, trademarks and reserves all rights, IP and copyright to freeprizedraws.ie and fpd.ie at all times.

Freeprizedraws is committed to protecting your privacy rights at all times and recognises that your privacy and the protection of your personal information is important to you and we will ensure that your personal data is handled and maintained in a secure and data protection compliant environment at all times.

DataXcel Ltd is registered with the Office Of The Data Protection Commissioner in Ireland as a Data Controller and Data Processor Registration No: 11223/A

To obtain information on the legislation governing data collection and processing in Ireland Go To: www.dataprivacy.ie

Freeprizedraws will not use or share your personal information in a manner that differs from what is described within this Privacy Statement and within the registration opt-in statement without your prior consent. The following consent statement is prominently displayed before you can join Freeprizedraws.

‘By ticking this box you understand and agree to all the [terms and conditions](https://www.fpd.ie/page/terms-and-conditions) and our [privacy policy](https://www.fpd.ie/page/privacy-policy). By registering with Freeprizedraws you agree to be contacted by Freeprizedraws and by carefully selected [third parties](https://www.fpd.ie/thirdparties.html) for marketing purposes and understand you can be contacted by telephone, mobile, email and postal. You can unsubscribe from such communications at any time. A List of the Third parties is listed on the consent statement on the web site. 

**By clicking the words third partes**  you can visit a list of marketing companies that may contact you for marketing purposes by post,mobile,landline,sms and email allowing you the choice to join our database or not. 

To view your unsubscribe options go to the my preference page on Freeprizedraws or view your marketing preferences [HERE](https://www.fpd.ie/unsubscribe)  

Once you register with Freeprizedraaws you consent to Freeprizedraws, the sponsors of Questions on the registration form which are listed [HERE](https://www.fpd.ie/brandpartners.html) and website brand sponsors being able to send you communications via email, post, SMS or telephone, until such times as you exercise your right to opt-out of receiving such communications. Also you are giving your permission for us to share your information with third parties At registration you have the option to opt-in to our Website Sponsors of Freeprizedraaws Website Sponsors have their own privacy policies and some have their own opt-in statements, it is strongly recommended that you read and understand this information.

You can view a list of our website sponsors [HERE](https://www.fpd.ie/brandpartners.html)

Every time you visit the website or use the service and provide us with information, by doing so you are accepting the policies and practices described in this Privacy Policy at that time. 

To update your preferences

Go To: <http://bit.ly/1qJibtk>

**Who this applies to**

This policy applies to individuals who have registered with Freeprizedraws and websites which Freeprizedraws provides prize draw services too. This policy was last reviewed: August 2016.

**What this applies to**

We collect the information you choose to provide during your registration process and the information provided when entering prize draws, quizzes and competitions.

**Use of your personal information**

We use your personal information collected via the Freeprizedraws.ie to:

  * Provide you with information about the products and services we offer
  * Provide you with a more personalised service
  * Conduct market research
  * Run prize draws and promotions
  * Pass on to selected companies to provide you with other offers and promotions relevant to the profile details you provided at registration.
  * Help other companies profile and extend their databases
  * Facilitate communication between yourself and others
  * For analysis purposes or to build data products. In these instances, the information is aggregated and wherever possible anonymised in line with the Data Protection Commissioner’s code of practice. Again, these products are of a marketing nature.

We may pass your personal data to the specified organisations to which you have consented and to carefully selected third party brands like [these brands ](https://www.fpd.ie/thirdparties.html) where we aim to match your profile to offers we think you will be interested in and we and they may contact you to discuss selling you further goods and services.

Here is a summary of industry sectors that may contact you. 

Charitable Organisations,

General Retailers

Mobile Telecommunication

Comparison Websites

Household Goods and Services

Travel and Leisure Pursuits

Competition Sites

Insurance Providers

Electric, Gas, Water and Multi-Utilities

Personal Injury

General Marketing

Financial Providers

Fashion and Leisure Goods

Health and Welfare

Food and Drink Producers and Retailers

We may process your personal data ourselves or through data processors that will process data on our behalf (in which case we will remain responsible for ensuring the data processor complies with this policy and all current data protection regulations).

We are registered with the appropriate data protection authorities and comply with all data protection and industry regulations.

We pay particular attention to the 2011 Electronic EU regulation and new regulations released by the ODPC around originator’s consent and the tweleve month rule.

We strictly observe the tweleve month.

We have appointed a Data Protection Officer at Freeprizedraws to ensure our data collection and our use of data complies fully with the relevant data protection regulations in place and protects your rights at all times. If you have any queries or need further information on the data we hold on you do contact our data protection officer on [datacompliance@dataxcel.ie](mailto:datacompliance@Freeprizedraws.ie)

We are also preparing our company in preparation for the new EU wide DP legislation expected to be released in May 2018

We will only use your personal data: - fairly and lawfully; - as set out in the Official Rules and/or this Policy; -to the extent necessary for these purposes.

Each questionnaire on Freeprizedraws is sponsored by a client. By giving a positive response and entering the questionnaire you are giving your consent for the sponsor / client to process the information you have provided and to send you information about products and/or services that may be of interest to you. The information you provide may be used, by Freeprizedraws and its Clients, to provide you with information and offers by email, Post, SMS, Mobile phone or Landline Telephone. If you would prefer NOTt to receive such offers, from Freeprizedraws, please indicate your preference by going to the my preference page http://bit.ly/XvJfzE

**Co - Sponsors Brands**

**Freeprizedras also work with sponsor clients where we share your data once you provide consent to do so. A list of the sponsor brands are listed on the consent statement and can also be viewed[HERE   ](https://www.fpd.ie/brandpartners.html)**

Commercially we aim to match your profile to relevant brand partner offers so the information you receive is relevant and within the context of your life stage and available purchasing power. For Example’ If you have provided your car insurance renewal data and have consented for third parties to contact you about one month before your renewal date we will work with third party brand partners to send you a car insurance quote tailored to your needs saving you time researching the market in full’  

Your data may be provided to clients of Freeprizedraws to be appended to information they already hold about you for the purpose of contacting you with information about their products and services. When first contacting you these clients will seek your appropriate consent.

**Ads that appear on freeprizedraws.ie**

Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to your website or other websites.  
    Google's use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.  
    Users may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting Ads Settings on your google account. (Alternatively, you can opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting www.aboutads.info.)

**Opting Out (Deregistration)**

Should you wish to opt out of your data being used for these purposes, please go [Here](https://www.fpd.ie/unsubscribe)

The consequences of opting out are that your account details will be placed in a do not contact file and you will not receive any further communications from Freeprizedraws. Every email that Freeprizedraws sends you contains a link to assist you update your contact preferences and a link to this privacy policy.

**Opting out at a later date**

Once you have given your consent, you can however still control whether or not you continue to receive communications or see such advertisements from such third parties. You can unsubscribe or opt out from any communicatons from Freeprizedraws or any third party brand at any time and we have listed below the optons open to you.

**Post**

You can withdraw your consent for  **postal marketing**  from anyone by adding your details to the  **Mail Preference Service.**  For more details please go to www.idma.ie

**E-mail or SMS (text message)**

You can unsubscribe from receiving  **e-mail or SMS marketing communications  **from any individual third party by using the instructions in any email communication such third party sends you  **(usually an ‘unsubscribe’ or ‘STOP’ link)**.

**Telephone calls**

To withdraw your consent for  **live or automated calls  **from anyone you can add your name to the  **Telephone Preference Service  **which is maintained under contract by eir go [HERE](http://www.openeir.ie/NDD/) for more information

You can also opt out at any time from communications via any of the methods described above by e-mailing us datacompliance@freeprizedraws.ie or support@fpd.ie **.**  Please note that such opt-out will only apply to communications from those third parties with whom we have a business relationship. If you opt out this way, you may still receive communications from third parties with whom we have no relationship.

**Social media and online**

You can configure your advertising preferences on social media such as Facebook, Twitter, Instagram or Pinterest by accessing your settings or preference options on the relevant platform. If you no longer want to receive personalized advertising on any website you visit, you can usually opt out directly through the privacy policy of the particular website you are accessing. Please note that this will not block ads that are displayed on the websites you visit, it will simply stop you receiving advertising that has been tailored to your interests. This opt-out relies on a cookie, so if you wipe all your cookies then that website will no longer know that you have opted out. The same applies if you use a different internet browser, or use a new computer to access the internet. You can also opt out of such advertising by visiting the IAB opt-out platform.

**Retention and destruction of personal data**

We will ensure that your personal data is not used unless it is accurate and up to date and we will not keep it for longer than necessary. Once it has been decided that the information is no longer needed it will be deleted promptly. The personal data, which we will use, is the information provided at registration and the data you provide when entering prize draws, quizzes and competitions and whether you have consented to be contacted by specified organisations. You may change your consents at any time – see the Official Rules.

**Security and storage of your personal information**

The Internet is not a 100% secure medium for communication and, accordingly, Freeprizedraws cannot guarantee the security of any information you send to Freeprizedraws via the Internet. Freeprizedraws is not responsible for any loss or damage you or others may suffer as a result of the loss of confidentiality of such information.

DataXcel Ltd may from time to time use third party suppliers to provide all or part of a service to you. DataXcel Ltd will only supply such of your personal information as is necessary to enable them to provide the relevant service to you. You should be aware that such outside service providers might be based in countries outside the European Union whose laws provide for a different standard of protection for your personal data than that provided under Irish law. In such circumstance DataXcel Ltd will have in place contractual arrangements or a Data Processing agreement which will require your data to be processed to a standard compliant with the Data Protection Legislation that exists in Ireland under the 1988 act,amaendements t the act of 2003 and the eprivacy regulations of 2011. DataXcel will not release your data to a non EU country with out processing proper due dilligence on the standards of data protection within the specificed country and always insist on proof of compliance with the Data Protection Act of 1988 and amendments to the act of 2003.  

**Your choices/options in relation to personal data**

You have the right to: - obtain access to your personal data; - receive information about us and the purposes for which we process your personal data; - prevent processing which may cause you damage or distress; - object to direct marketing; - object to purely automated decision-making in certain cases; - you have the right to seek compensation through the civil courts for a breach of a data controller’s obligations; - ask us to correct any errors and/or delete the information we hold - opt out of any further contact. If you would like to amend/delete details or contact us in relation to the above, please contact using the contact us page.

**Contact Security**

We have appropriate security measures in place to protect against loss, misuse, or alteration of information that we have collected. We also require third parties with whom we share information to keep this information secure and work on a data processor agreement process with any third party data contractors.

**IP Address & Cookies**

We automatically collect your IP address and record the web page from which you originated if you are using the service’s website. Cookies are used to increase your security, not infringe on your privacy. In order to monitor, facilitate, administer and optimise the website and service for users and to earmark any possible technical issues that may arise within the website or the service. 

We may use your IP address to help identify you, tend to any difficulties and to gather demographic and profile information. We also use the ‘cookies’ to collect information about your online activity on our website, such as the web pages you visit, the links you click, and the searches you conduct on our website. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can modify your web browser

setting to decline cookies. If you choose to do this you may not be able to avail of some or all of the functionalities that the website or the service may offer. If you have any queries about this information:

## Liability of DataXcel

Material displayed on the Website is provided without any guarantees, conditions or warranties. DataXcel will not be liable for interruptions to operations or any other interference, including technical interference, over which it has no control. Further, DataXcel does not accept responsibility for errors in the data you enter including your registration details. This includes, but is not limited to, submission errors caused by transmission failures; delays; typographical errors; telephone or network failures; computer, electronic, or Internet hardware or software failures: the inability of any site to accept all of DataXcel's data; and tampering. DataXcel does not provide any assurance or guarantee that you will win prizes in any draw, or at all.

Whilst DataXcel takes reasonable measures to detect and eliminate viruses from the Website, DataXcel cannot ensure that the website will be free from viruses and does not accept any liability in this respect. You are recommended to take all appropriate measures before downloading or accessing information from the Website including social media and search engine security meausres.

Users cannot knowingly use the site to introduce virus and Trojans

You must not misuse the Website by knowingly introducing viruses, trojans, worms or other material which is malicious or technologically harmful. You must not attempt to gain unauthorised access to the Website, the server on which the Website is stored or any server, computer or database connected to the Website. You must not attack the Website via a denial-of-service attack or a distributed denial-of-service attack. By breaching this provision, you would commit a criminal offence under the Computer Misuse Act 1990. DataXcel will report any such breach to the relevant law enforcement authorities and will cooperate with those authorities by disclosing your identity to them. In the event of such a breach, your right to use the Website will cease immediately. DataXcel will not be liable for any loss or damage caused by a distributed denial-of-service attack, viruses or other technologically harmful material that may infect your computer equipment, computer programs, data or other proprietary material due to your use of the Website or use of any website linked to it. However DataXcel will take adequate measures from their end to ensure that such incidents do not occur.

Contact us by:

Post: Data Compliance  Dept., Freeprizedraws C/O Dataxcel Ltd,29 Lower Patrick Street, Kilkenny, County Kilkenny, Republic Of Ireland

By email: [datacompliance@dataxcel.ie](mailto:datacompliance@Winnersville.co.uk%20)

By Telephone: 00353 56 779 0295
